Guide to the Louis Dupree Papers, 1943 - 1989, undated UA.29.02.0037
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Writings and Research, 1947-1989, undated
  - Other Writings and Research, 1947-1989, undated
    - Village Interview Transcripts, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 173)
      Typed transcript of an interview with an Indian villager, plus appendices and handwritten notes.
    - Voice of America, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 174)
      Handwritten draft by Dupree for a Voice of America program marking the anniversary of the Soviet invasion of Afghanistan.
    - Wall Street Journal, letter and clippings, 1987-1988 (Box 2, Folder 175)
    - Washington Post, letter, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 176)
  - Dupree Interview Transcripts, 1978, 1980
    - Transcript of Tapes: Prison Experience, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 177)
      Note by Nancy Hatch Dupree: Transcript of tapes made by Louis Dupree in Peshawar immediately following his imprisonment in Kabul, December 1978.
    - Afghanistan: A Conversation with Dr. Louis Dupree, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 178)
  - Fellowships and Grants 1983-1989
    - American Institute of Pakistani Studies, 1983-1989 (Box 3, Folder 179)
      Correspondence, application, proposal, notes, and other materials related to the Duprees' study of Afghan refugees in Pakistan.
    - Ford Foundation Grant: The First Russo-Afghan War, 1983-1988, undated (Box 3, Folder 180)
      Correspondence, proposal, and other materials related to Dupree's unfinished book, The First Russo-Afghan War (1979-???): Afghan Cultural Responses to the Soviet Occupation.
    - Ford Foundation Grant: The Modernization of Inner Asia, 1985-1987 (Box 3, Folder 181)
      Grant proposal to the Ford Foundation for funding for the book The Modernization of Inner Asia. Annotations by Dupree.
    - Ford Foundation Grant: Refugees and General, 1982-1984, undated (Box 3, Folder 182)
      Correspondence, proposal, tentative outline of book, notes, and other materials related to the Duprees' study of Afghan refugees in Pakistan.
    - Fulbright Scholar Award, 1988-1989 (Box 3, Folder 183)
      Correspondence, application, and other materials related to the Duprees' study of Afghan refugees in Pakistan.
  - Reviews, 1986-1988
    Materials related to Dupree serving as an advisor and reviewer on journal articles, books, and a master's thesis. Includes correspondence, notes, and abstracts and drafts of articles and books under consideration.
    - Central Asia Survey: Sultana Afroz 1988 (Box 3, Folder 184)
    - Foreign Policy Association: Pakistan and Afghanistan: Storm Over Southwest Asia, Great Decisions, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 185)
    - International Center for Dynamics of Development: Dana D. Reynolds, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 186)
    - International Migration Review: Factors in the Residential Choices of Self-Settled Afghan Refugees in Peshawar, Pakistan, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 187)
    - National Council of the Churches of Christ, Afghanistan primer, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 188)
    - Nemec, Margaret: Thesis and Independent Study, 1987-1988 (Box 3, Folder 189)
    - New York Times: A Reporter at Large: The Catastrophe, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 190)
    - Northwestern University Press: Report on Afghanistan by Jeri Laber, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 191)
    - Orkand Corporation: The Soviets in Afghanistan: Adapting, Reappraising, and Settling In, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 192)
    - Oxford University Press, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 193)
      Correspondence, comments by Dupree on a manuscript by Barnett Rubin entitled The Struggle for the Afghan State: Communist Coup d'Etat and Islamic Revolution. Correspondence and comments by Dupree on a manuscript by Michael Karasz entitled Strewn Along Shores.
    - Peshawar University references, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 194)
    - Rubin, Barnett: Lineages of the State in Afghanistan, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 195)
    - Western Political Quarterly: President Carter and the Invasion of Afghanistan, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 196)
  - Thesis, 1954
    - Thesis (Box 3, Folder 197-198)
      Two bound volumes of Dupree's Ph.D. dissertation, Harvard University Dept. of Anthropology: Shamshir Ghar: Historic Cave Site in Kandahar Province, Afghanistan, 1954
- Teaching and university materials, 1977-1989, undated
  Correspondence, syllabi, reading lists, notes, student papers, and other materials related to Dupree's teaching career.
  - Courses, 1977-1989, undated (Box 3, Folder 199)
  - Duke University, 1987-1989 (Box 3, Folder 200)
  - Duke University: Activities Reports, 1985-1988 (Box 3, Folder 201)
  - Duke University: Anthropology 180.1, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 202)
  - Duke University: Political Science 235S, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 203)
  - Duke University: University Research Council, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 204)
  - Institute for Asian Studies Brochure, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 205)
  - PSU: Central Asia, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 206)
  - University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill: Anthropology 120, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 207)
  - University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill: Anthropology 137, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 208)
  - University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill: PPS 195.01 Regional Ethnic Conflicts, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 209)
  - West Point, 1984-1985 (Box 3, Folder 210)
- Personal Materials, 1943-1944, 1982-1988, undated
  - Armed Forces Service, 1943-1944, 1982-1988, undated
    - 11th Airborne, 1982-1985, undated (Box 3, Folder 211)
      Correspondence, notes, clippings, maps, and other materials related to Dupree's service in the 11th Airborne Division.
    - 187th Airborne, 1985-1987, undated (Box 3, Folder 212)
      Correspondence, clippings, and other materials related to Dupree's service in the 187th Airborne Division.
    - Army, 1985-1988, undated (Box 3, Folder 213)
      Correspondence, copies of Dupree's discharge records, and other materials related to Dupree's U. S. Army service.
    - Cadet Midshipman Log and Scrapbook, 1943-44 (Box 3, Folder 214)
      Scrapbook kept by Dupree during his 1943-1944 armed forces service. Includes journal entries, verse, clippings, photographs, and other memorabilia.
  - Family 1981-1988
    - Dupree Family Album 1984 (Box 3, Folder 215)
      Correspondence regarding The Dupree Family Album and a copy of The Name and Family of Dupre(e) from the Roots Research Bureau.
    - Greenville, N.C. 1981-1988 (Box 3, Folder 216)
      Clipping about the Duprees from the Greenville Daily Reflector, Greenville High School reunion program, letters, and other personal materials.